Igor Salimzhanov

Belgrade, Serbia



mail@isalimzhanov.me



linkedin.com/in/igor-salimzhanov

Summary

Adaptable Business Analyst with extensive experience in the tech industry, specializing in data consolidation, data analysis, requirements analysis, and integration between internal and external information systems. Proficient in technical writing, software failure analysis, and problem-solving, with a customer-centric approach and excellent communication skills.

Experience



Leading Business Analyst

Committee of Finance of Saint Petersburg

Feb 2022 - Mar 2023 (1 year 2 months)

- Authored user documentation for seven services, updated documentation for four APIs, and developed seven agreements and regulations for information interaction between internal and external systems;
- Designed a complex risk assessment, compliance, and business intelligence system for Saint Petersburg and Moscow regions, incorporating 70 data sources, seven new services, and catering to over 5,000 users, reducing waiting time for applicants from several days to one hour;
- Implemented application integrations between internal and external information systems, improving data dynamics understanding and enhancing data-driven decision-making quality;
- Prepared technical correspondence on planned system updates, focusing on efficiency, predictability, and seamless system interactions.

Leading Site Reliability Engineer

Department of the Federal Treasury for Saint Petersburg

Jul 2012 - Feb 2022 (9 years 8 months)

- Managed and supported the operation of software applications for internal and external clients;
- Analyzed failures and violations in software systems, developed proposals for their elimination and prevention.

Education



GeekBrains

System Administrator, Administration of Computer Systems and Information **Technologies** Sep 2021 - Sep 2022

GeekBreins

Automation Testing Engineer, Software Development Oct 2018 - Jun 2019

GeekBrains

Testing Engineer, Software Development Jan 2018 - Sep 2018

St. Petersburg State University of Economics

Specialist degree, Accounting, analysis and audit 2005 - 2008 Institute of Economics and Management of Service Enterprises, Daytime/Full-time

Licenses & Certifications

Implementation of the public services platform - The Russian Presidential Academy of National Economy and Public Administration (RANEPA) 2270-2022-У-ЦПРиКЦТ

Skills

Project Control • Business Process Improvement • Analytical Skills • Deadline Management • Data Analysis • Business Process Design • Requirements Analysis • API Documentation • Technical Documentation • Business Analysis